<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Intellegent_Finance_App</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="mutual_funds">
Mutual funds are created when several people who wish to earn wealth (investors) combine their resources to create a huge investable amount (corpus). This large corpus is then invested into various companies across industries, operating in different sectors of the economy - depending on the type of fund chosen.
All the investors of a mutual fund share in its profits, losses, incomes, and expenses in direct proportion to their level of investment.
Let’s say that there’s a huge national demand for 50 lakh units of bottled water per month, but the water bottling plant can only produce 1 lakh units per month. Suppose that the bottling plant can meet this demand if it has a new bottling machine - it can earn a massive profit from supplying the demand. Unfortunately, the bottling plant does not have the funds to purchase this new machine - so it seeks investment. This is an opportunity for a win-win situation for any investor who has enough wealth to help the bottling plant purchase the machine. In most cases, individual investors won’t have the requisite funds to purchase large machinery, so, a few investors get together and pool their funds to buy the machine, and will split all profits equally amongst themselves, or in proportion of the amount they’ve invested.
This basically explains how an investment helps a company grow, but mutual funds take it a step further. Mutual funds don’t just invest in one or two companies, but in hundreds of companies across different sectors of the economy. In addition to the bottling plant, the same mutual fund scheme may have invested in a transportation company, enabling quicker movement of bottled water from the factory to the distribution centres. In addition to the transportation company, the same mutual fund scheme could also have invested in an advertising agency that promotes the sale of this particular brand of bottled water - ensuring smooth sales from distribution centre to end customer. In this way, a mutual fund takes care of most aspects of its investment and tries to ensure its success. Now since it’s a mutual fund, it can have two options by which investors can enjoy their profits - growth or dividend. Under the growth option, all earnings made by the fund are reinvested in the fund itself, and the capital invested is allowed to grow until the tenure of the investment is completed or the investor chooses to redeem the investment. Under the dividend option, the bottling plant will declare income, and dividends will be distributed amongst the investors. Now, suppose that the demand for water suddenly dropped from 50 lakh units to 10 lakh units, but the machine had already been purchased and is now running on lower capacity, or the machine purchased was faulty, or there’s a labour strike preventing water from being bottled - the profits generated will not be as high as expected, and returns for investors will be low, and investors could also lose money. This is called a risk factor, and is one of the major defining characteristics of any mutual fund scheme. Risk must be thoroughly studied in order to mitigate it, and even then, great care must be taken to invest the right amount at the right time in the right place.
</string>
    <string name="sign_out">Sign out</string>
</resources>
